<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Creating Components on</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/</link><description>Recent content in Creating Components on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Bash component</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/bash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/bash/</guid><description>In this tutorial, you’ll create a component that does the following:
Extract all hyperlinks from a markdown file Check if every URL is reachable Create a text report with the results The component will be able to run locally and as a docker container. In order to create a component you need two files: a script for the functionality and a config file that describes the component.
The files used in this tutorial can be found here:</description></item><item><title>Creating a Python component</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/python/</guid><description>NOTICE: This documentation might be outdated. Please be patient while the tutorial is being rewritten.
The first step of developing this component, is writing the core functionality of the component, in this case a Python script.
Write a script in Python This is a simple script which prints a simple message, along with any input provided to it through the par[&amp;quot;input&amp;quot;] parameter. Optionally, you can override the greeter with par[&amp;quot;greeter&amp;quot;].</description></item><item><title>Creating an R component</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/r/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/creating_components/r/</guid><description>NOTICE: This documentation might be outdated. Please be patient while the tutorial is being rewritten.
The first step of developing this component, is writing the core functionality of the component, in this case an R script.
Write a script in R This is a simple script which prints a simple message, along with any input provided to it through the par[&amp;quot;input&amp;quot;] parameter. Optionally, you can override the greeter with par[&amp;quot;greeter&amp;quot;].</description></item></channel></rss>