<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://viash.io/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/introduction/</guid><description>By providing some meta-data regarding its functionality and the platform on which you want to run the software, viash can help you:
Wrap your script in an executable with a CLI and --help functionality. Seamlessly execute your component natively on the host platform or in a Docker container. Combine multiple components in a Nextflow pipeline. Unit-test your component to ensure that it works at all times. Example use cases Here are a few use cases which serve as motivation for viash:</description></item><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/installation/</guid><description>Supported Operating Systems You can run viash on the following operating systems:
Linux macOS Windows using Windows Subsystem for Linux Prerequisites viash is developed in Scala 2.12, so you’ll need an Oracle Java SE Runtime Environment 8 installation or OpenJDK in order to use it. Installing viash Packaged release To install viash, download the latest release and save it to the ~/bin folder or any other directory that is specified your $PATH variable.</description></item><item><title>Supported languages</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/supported_languages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/supported_languages/</guid><description>To get started with your preferred language, take a look at the language specific examples below.
Bash Bash Hello World example: An introduction to how viash works using a variation on the classic “Hello World” programming example. This example is written specifically for Bash. Creating a Bash component: This tutorial explains how to create your own viash component from scratch using a Bash script at its core. Python Python Hello World example: An introduction to how viash works using a variation on the classic “Hello World” programming example.</description></item><item><title>Hello World (Bash)</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/hello_world_bash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/hello_world_bash/</guid><description>Prerequisites To follow along with this tutorial, you need to have this software installed on your machine:
An installation of viash. A Bash Unix shell. Running the component You can run a simple ‘Hello World’ component by running the following command:
URL=https://viash.io/examples/hello_world/config.vsh.yaml viash run $URL Hello world! Every component accepts –help as an option, which outputs a description of the component and a list of accepted options.</description></item><item><title>Hello World (Python)</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/hello_world_python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/hello_world_python/</guid><description>Prerequisites To follow along with this tutorial, you need to have this software installed on your machine:
An installation of viash. A Bash Unix shell. An installation of python 3. You may have to install the python-is-python3 package on Ubuntu and its derivatives to make Python 3 the default version. Running the component You can run a simple ‘Hello World’ component by running the following command:
URL=https://viash.io/examples/hello_world_py/config.vsh.yaml viash run $URL Hello world!</description></item><item><title>Hello World (R)</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/hello_world_r/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/prologue/hello_world_r/</guid><description>Hello world We have provided a simple Hello World component as an introduction to viash. Follow the steps below to learn how to run a component and get a result back from it.
Prerequisites To follow along with this tutorial, you need to have this software installed on your machine:
An installation of viash. A Bash Unix shell. An installation of the R software environment Running the component You can run a simple ‘Hello World’ component by running the following command:</description></item></channel></rss>