<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/introduction/</guid><description>By providing some meta-data regarding its functionality and the platform on which you want to run the software, Viash can help you:
Wrap your script in an executable with a CLI and --help functionality. Seamlessly execute your component natively on the host platform or in a Docker container. Combine multiple components in a Nextflow pipeline. Unit-test your component to ensure that it works at all times. Example use cases Here are a few use cases which serve as motivation for Viash:</description></item><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/installation/</guid><description>Supported Operating Systems You can run Viash on the following operating systems:
Linux macOS Windows using Windows Subsystem for Linux Prerequisites Viash is developed in Scala 2.12, so you’ll need an Oracle Java SE Runtime Environment 8 installation or OpenJDK in order to use it. You will need Docker to install Viash and use it to its full potential. Installing Viash To install Viash to a bin folder in your current directory, run the following command to download and run the bootstrap tool:</description></item><item><title>What is a Viash Component?</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/what_is_a_viash_component/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/getting_started/what_is_a_viash_component/</guid><description>Prerequisites To follow along with this tutorial, you need to have this software installed on your machine:
An installation of Viash. A Bash Unix shell. Running the component You can run a simple ‘Hello World’ component by running the following command:
URL=https://viash.io/examples/hello_world/config.vsh.yaml viash run $URL Hello world! Every component accepts –help as an option, which outputs a description of the component and a list of accepted options.</description></item></channel></rss>