<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributing on</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/contributing/</link><description>Recent content in Contributing on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://viash.io/docs/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contributing Guidelines</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/contributing/guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/contributing/guidelines/</guid><description>We welcome any contributions to this project, be it changes in documentation, bug fixes, new functionality, or even new packages if they fit the scope of our project.
By participating in this project, you agree to abide by our code of conduct.
Contributing to Viash Help others A great way of contributing is helping others by providing answers and suggestions on their issues.
Test new releases We release new versions of Viash periodically that introduce improvements, features and bug fixes.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://viash.io/docs/contributing/conduct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://viash.io/docs/contributing/conduct/</guid><description>Our Pledge We as members, contributors, and leaders pledge to make participation in our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, visible or invisible disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
We pledge to act and interact in ways that contribute to an open, welcoming, diverse, inclusive, and healthy community.</description></item></channel></rss>